# **Aggarat Jaisook**

+66 817143082 • aggarat@hotmail.com • Thailand 11/2 The Colory Vivid Condo Huaykwang Huaykwang Bangkok Thailand

# IT Director, Chief Architect, Head of Development

#### SUMMARY

Decisive, action-oriented and result-focused professional offering over 12 years of experience in IT software development industry with over 6 years of software/solution architect experience. Offer strong leadership and successful team building skills. Management background includes leading teams, developing and managing budgets, monitoring project standards for all deliverable, creating strategies, overseeing technical design, documentation, conducting training, and maintaining quality assurance and multi-national working experiences. Proven technical background includes software architecture, software development, object-oriented analysis and design, requirements analysis, and data modeling. and experiences in MASSIVE and CRITICAL scaling with No.1 Internet company(Sanook.com) ,No.2 Mobile Operator (TrueCorp) and No.1 Retail Company (CP Group) in Thailand.

# **EMPLOYMENT OBJECTIVE**

A position as a IT Director, Chief Architect or Head of Development that will allow me to apply my communication, managerial and technical skills and experience in production of leading-edge information solutions.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- TRUE ID, the single sign on system that combine customer profiles and customer experiences into only one system to support CRM on TRUE MOVE(H), TRUE MONEY, TRUE VISION, TRUE INTERNET, TRUE WIFI and TRUELIFE (Core product for True corporation).
- Data Platform, the big data analytics services for Ascend and CPGroup. Storing terabytes of data which can be queried and analylized by BU.
- **CPONE ID**, the single sign on/loyalty system that supports point exchange, point management and CRM for CP GROUP the biggest retail in Thailand
- Content Provider Platform (VAS platform) the system that support content providers, operator and customer to sale ,promote or buy digital products or phisical products with complex business rules and all access channels(web,wap,app and tv).(Replacement SK telecom software) with Cloud and virtualization concept, as a core team 100% design, development and operation.(True Corporation)
- Support True Music Store Application and True H Music on Mobile Application iPhone and Android.
- Implemented D/W business and usage report / Revenue Sharing of operator and content provider and True Convergence KPI Report. (True Corporation)

- Critical data mgration transforming to open source products for cost deduction(Sanook.com). (Migrate data MSSQL to MySql and NoSql(MongoDb))(Sanook.com)
- As a project manager, I delivered effective, efficient and reliable IT solutions to the company customers on time and within the budget with over 22 products in past 3 years (Sanook.com)..
- Implemented platform application and critical core system in the company (Ex: Mail System can send out email over 100,000 mail a day, Web member system with over 15,000,000 records, Backend system, APIs handles read/write operation more than 22,500 requests/s/server) (Sanook.com).
- Handled over 600 Change Requests and over 2000 trouble tickets for product implementation in the past (Sanook.com)..
- Expertise in Object Oriented Analysis and Design, Service Oriented Architectures ,Agile Methodology(Scrum, Extreme Programming ) and Traditional SDLC (Sanook.com)..
- International Co-operate with Tencent (QQ), The largest internet company in China in critical Time and High Scalability (Sanook.com)..
- Work as a consultant for IT solution and knowledge exchange in MIH GROUP (Sanook.com).
- With R&D assignment for the company, Brought special techniques and software architecture for high availability and massive(over 10,000,000 requests/day api server) concurrency which are widely used in many products in the company (Sanook.com)..
- Re-Architected Network System Infra Application of Organization (Sanook.com).
- Established Business and Process Tools (WorkFlow, Trouble Ticket, Change Request and Control) for Organization (True Corp).

# **SKILLS**

- VAS IT implementation, operation and management with Operator and Content Provider business rule understanding.
- Enterprise System Architect, Mission Critical Project Management and Technical Solution.
- Cloud and Microservices Architecture and Containerization of existing services. (AWS and Google Cloud Platform)
- IT Product and Project Management, Team Building and Leadership, Multi-site Team Management (Sanook.com).
- UML, Object Oriented Design, Rational Unified Process. Cloud Architectures. Service Oriented. (Tools: Enterprise Architecture Design, Visio, EDrawMax).
- As system Analyst functionality ,SDLC, SCRUM, and other agile development process.(Tools: Microsoft Project, Open Project, MS Excel, RedMine)
- C#, PHP, Python and ASP.NET,C++ H/W embed programming, Wireless Network programing .Net technologies, Data Analysis tools(Several Products) and Linux Programming & Administration and Database Software(VS Studio 2005,MSSQL 2000-2008)
- Web Interface Engineering with XML, HTML, CSS and JavaScript: Several Frameworks and Web Pages
  Measurement tools and Tracking system(Framework: JQuery, HTML5 | Tools:PageSpeed, Firebug,
  YSlow, Manage Engine Opmanager).

• Process improvement knowledge such as QA, CC, CR, Software Configuration Management and Documentation Tools(Tools: MS Sharepoint, Service Desk Plus and tWiki).

# Technology Contribution / Evangelist

- Owner of BigData Thailand Facebook's Page and Big Data Group which has 6000+ members. https://www.facebook.com/pages/Bigdata/336405566451770
- Organizer of Bangkok BigData Meetup http://www.meetup.com/Bangkok-Big-Data-Meetup/
- Owner of DockerThailand Facebook's Page and DockerThailand Group https://www.facebook.com/pages/DockerThailand/641802952588593

## **SOFTWARE**

- -Strong both enterprise software stacks and opensource stacks-
  - Software Management: Jira, Gitlab and Jenkins
  - Clouds: AWS, Google Cloud Platform and Container Technology (Dockers)
  - Development Tools: IntelliJ, Sublime, Microsoft Visual Studio
  - UML Modeling: Rational Rose, Microsoft Visio, Sparx Enterprise Architeture.
  - Databases/Datastore: ORACLE, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, Postgresql, Tokyo Tyrant Tokyo Cabinet, Redis, MongoDB, Cassandra, MemSQL and Hazelcast
  - Platforms: Linux, Windows, Android, OSX.
  - Vendors: Oracle, IBM, Hauwei etc.

## EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

# Solutions Architect/Development Manager (Current) Ascend Group

- Report directly to CTO and COO
- Responsible for TrueID (The CRM,SSO system) which is the most important for the company(19M of customers).
- Responsible for Data Platform for building big data analytics platform for e-commerce business of Ascend Group. (Cloud Solutions) - iTrueMart, WLS,TrueID, CPone, Aden, Ascend Nano and TrueMoney
- Implement Data Analytics as Service (Data Lake, Dashboard, Data Science Tool) for Ascend Group.
- Responsible for TrueID Pay (Apple ID), The digital payment platform for True Corp.

- Implement CPOne ID , The ID system for CP Group.
- Trainer of Software Engineer / Practices for new joiners.
- Solution Architect of mission critical platform and massive concurrent users.
- Managing 4 squads(Scrum teams) TrueID, Data Platform, CPOne and TrueCloud over 24 people.

#### Solutions Architect/Development Manager (2009-2014)

**True Corporation Public Company Limited** (Convergence), Thailand - One of biggest mobile operator in Thailand.

- Report directly to CIO & Department size is over 800 staffs.
- Responsible for TrueID (The CRM,SSO system) which is the most important for the company(19M of customers).
- Responsible for **Data Analytics Team** for building **big data analytics** platform for e-commerce business / content business of **True**
- Enterprise Architecture Design and Development for large scale with high availability and complex integration between True Corporation TrueMove, TrueVision, TrueInternet, TrueMoney and TrueLife.
- Designed and Implemented VAS platform system (SK Telecom System Replacement, The Software invested 30M THB.) which is the core business of True Convergence, ex True Music Store, TrueBook, True Movie etc. VAS platform supports over 200+ Mobile Applications in Apple Store and Play Store.
- Designed and Implemented Mobile Application Back-end for True Appcenter(True's Mobile Applications around 200 Applications).
- Designed and Implemented D/W of Financial Report of VAS for the company.
- Enterprise Architecture Design and Development for large scale with high availability and mission critical.
- Training IT staffs with new technology and tools for development(as Web scaling, NoSql Trainer, Architecture Trainer and Web and Mobile Performance Improvement).
- Replacement of Commercial products by open sources for cost deduction (Replace EMC, Gluster FS).
- Application Platform building for reuse and long live application (True Platform APIs) which provides service among True Companies.
- Virtalization and Cloud implementation for reducing the operation cost. (VMware ESX, XEN)
- Public Clouds Experts such as AWS and Google Cloud Platform.
- Social Networking Analyst. Viral Marketing and Social Network Marketing Expert (FB connect).
- Implement KPIs Report for all products in organization (MSSQL 2008, Tabluea and Google BigQuery).
- Implement Analytic Reports and Business Intelligence (Microsoft BI(SSAS,SSIS),Pentaho).

#### IT Manager (2006-2009)

**Sanook Online Limited** (www.sanook.com), Thailand - The number 1 website in Thailand, Responsible for software development of company specializing in web technology.

- Successfully initiated and managed several highly visible projects within the organization. (Thaimate.com, Playtown.sanook.com, member.sanook.com, widget.sanook.com,mail.sanook.com etc.)
- Develop and Maintenance core system. Able to handle over 20,000 requests/s (High Concurrency)(
   Sanook Member System, SMS MMS gateway, Mail Gateway, Social Network Platform APIs: 22 products plus)
- Software Architecture and System Analysis for APIs (Massive Scaling). Over 10M page views a day
- Assembled and managed multidisciplinary project teams for product development.
- Provided employee development, coaching, mentoring, and team building.
- Training and Coaching Developers. (PHP,C# and Python).
- Linux Socket Programming for scaling Web Application.
- Research and Development Social Network Applications and Web 2.0 Application.
- Built product & service KPI report / Analytic Services: Internal Development aggregate with Truehits.net, Google Analytics, Omiture Site catalyst.
- Training IT staffs with new technology and tools for development (as NoSql Trainer, Architecture Trainer and Web Performance Improvement Trainer).

# Software Project Leader (2004-2006)

#### URL Co., Ltd, Thailand

- •. Successfully implement E-Commerce System for the biggest pornography media company in Europe (PRIVATE MEDIA GROUP in NASDAQ) www.private.com
- •. Software project management.(SDLC,AGILE METHODOLOGY)
- Coordinated with other internal departments including Quality Assurance, Product Operations, and Production Support.
- Supervised and conducted architecture, design activities as well as code reviews.
- Provided employee development, coaching, mentoring, and team building. Over 12 staffs.
- Project Launching and Delivery to Customers.

# Research Assistant (2003 - 2004)

#### AIT Asian Institute of Technology, Thailand

- •. Work in Interlab (Internet Education and Research Laboratory) & DEC is the network laboratory and training center for AIT student
- •. Consolidate internet statistic in Thailand.
- Developed E-Learning Software for AIT student.
- Prepare Server and Network Infrastructure for simulation in the lab.
- Maintain lab website: reservation system, content management system.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **B.S.**, Computer Engineering

2002

Suranaree University of Technology, Thailand,

## M.S., Information Technology

2005

## **CERTIFICATIONS AND TRAININGS**

- Certified Scrum Master CSM (Agile Alliance)
- Certified Scrum Developer -CSD (Agile Alliance)
- Oracle Certified Associate (OCA)
- Microsoft 070-345 Web Application Visual C#
- TOEIC with score 780/990

## PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- AWS SUMMIT 2015, Singapore 2015
- AWS Architect, Bangkok Thailand 2015
- Certified Scrum Master, Bangkok Thailand 2015
- Certified Scurm Developer, Bangkok Thailand 2015
- Tencent Knowledge Exchange, ShenZhen China 2010
- Harvard University Business Training in Business Strategy Topic. Cape Town, South Africa 2008.
- MIH Group Technology Exchanged Knowledge (Cloud Computing and Web 2.0). Palo Alto, USA 2007.
- Technical Knowledge Transfer (IBIBO.COM). New Delhi, India.
- Server Vendor Factory Visit: Hewlett Packard, Singapore
- CommunicAsia, Enterprise IT 2009, Singapore
- Leadership Training. Bangkok, Thailand.
- IT Security and Software Process Improvement Training. Software Park, Thailand 2004.
- AFS Student Exchange Program. Florence, Italy 1997.

## PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of birth: 05 October 1980

Age 34. Single

Languages: fluent English, native Thailand.

Citizenship: Thai.

REFERENCES (Available upon request)